Phill Lin

Full Stack Developer

Dedicated and efficient full stack developer with 7+ years experience in application layers, presentation layers, and databases. Spearheaded successful transition from LAMP stack to MEAN which cut latency by 40% and increased effectiveness of database administrators by 20%. Seeking to further improve HTML5 and CSS3 skills as the future full stack developer at Atmospheric Solutions.



philljohnson739@gmail.com



Hong Kong

SKILLS

HTML5

CSS3

TypeScript

jQuery

Bootstrap

Angular

React

Vue

Express

Python

SQL

SAAS

Git

Photoshop

LANGUAGES

English















WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

Artis Technologies

03/2019 - Present Achievements/Tasks

Created a web application that allowed 75K users to search for nearby restaurants based on their location with 89% accuracy.

Dallas, Texas, US

Atlanta, Georgia, US

- Worked with a team of 27 developers that created an e-commerce website using React, Express, and MongoDB within 3 months.
- Participated in code reviews of 300 developers' ensuring that all code complied 100% with coding standards & best practices.
- Developed a responsive email template in HTML5 and CSS3 that increased the click through rate by 78%, an improvement fromprevious years.

Front End Developer

CharterUP

07/2017 - 02/2019

Achievements/Tasks

- Developed front-end code using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery to create a responsive web application that works across 29 devices, including desktops and tablets.
- Optimized 29 web pages for speed and performance by eliminating unnecessary scripts/styles and increasing load time by 69%.
- Created an interactive map for a real estate company's website that allowed 7K users to search by neighborhood and get real-time feedback about a property.
- Partnered with 28 UX designers on redesigning existing site; improving conversion rate by 77%.
- Maintained and updated 50+ existing websites to ensure compatibility with new technologies and standards.

Software Engineer

Tink Labs

06/2015 - 06/2017

Kwun Tong, HongKong Achievements/Tasks

- Designed and launched an automated testing framework using Python's unit test module, which reduced manual QA time from 9 weeks to 10 hours per release.
- Slashed development costs by creating reusable components such as database wrappers, and authentication modules, resulting in \$1Mannual savings for RWEC.
- Created a web application that allows 2.7K users to create and manage their online accounts for the products of RWEC, reducing customer support calls by 79%.
- Collaborated with front-end developers to ensure seamless integration of back-end functionality with user interfaces, resulting in a cohesive and user-friendly web application.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

09/2011 - 05/2015